Oleksandr Didenko

City: Nizhyn, Ukraine

Email: dreamcomes0704@gmail.com

Telegram: @olexdkdream

Skype: <u>dreamcomes0704@outlook.com</u> Phone Number: +380916214287

PROFILE

I am a full-stack web engineer with a decade's worth of experience and in the meantime, I worked on designing, developing, deploying, and maintaining websites and web applications by using these frameworks. I have deep knowledge of architecture for these frameworks.

Specifically, I have tones of experience in mobile-first focus frontend development, always document my code.

I started a career as a JavaScript developer always in search of new tools and better ways to solve challenging tasks for businesses and I love to learn new things.

That's helped me to grow to a tech lead position as a React, Laravel, Django developer, and to become a full-stack developer with solid knowledge in modern JS such as React, Angular, Vue and etc.

I always go out of my way to deliver the best quality!

SKILLS & EXPERIENCES

Skills and Experiences

- ✓ React.js, Gatsby.js, Next.js, Vue.js, Nuxt.js, Angular.js, Angular 2+
- ✓ HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, jQuery, Bootstrap, Canvas, MetronicUI.
- ✔ PHP, Laravel, CodeIgniter, OpenCart, WordPress
- ✓ Python, Django, Flask
- ✓ MySQL, DynamoDB, MongoDB, SQLite, PostgreSQL.
- ✓ RESTful API Development
- ✓ Unit Testing
- ✓ AWS EC2, S3, AWS Lambda Functions, AWS Amplify Cognito,

Firebase, Heroku, and etc.

- ✓ API integration (Google Maps, YouTube, Twitter, Facebook and etc.)
- ✔ Payment gateway integration (Stripe, PayPal, Google Pay, and etc.)
- ✓ Source Management by using GitHub, Bitbucket, Gitlab, SVN, etc.
- ✓ Task Management by using Trello, Jira, etc.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

February 2019 - December 2019

Django/Wagtail Full-Stack DEVELOPER At Polymerases Company - Part Time

• Developed and deployed tons of CMS websites by using Python, Django, Wagtail, Docker, Circle CI/CD

November 2018 - January 2019

PYTHON SCRAPING & CRAWELR DEVELOPER At Cambridge Energy Data Lab - Part Time

They asked me to build a lot of scrapers for the big ecommerce platforms and many web automations tools. I developed lots of scrapers/crawlers and web automatic bots by using Python, Selenium web driver, Beautiful Soup, PhantomJS, Cron service.

April 2017 - August 2018

FULL-STACK LARAVEL, DJANGO DEVELOPER At Eurocom Corporation - Full Time

A Board directors is a recognized group of people who jointly oversee the activities of an organization, which can be either a for-profit business, nonprofit organization, or a government agency. I've worked as full stack Laravel, Django developer. I developed admin dashboard, meeting, documents, voting. permission modules etc

September 2016 - May 2017

React.JS, CSS Expert with Django skills At Public Sector Pension Investment Board

Originating from research at the University of Cambridge, AIswitch is an intelligent program that finds better energy deals for every customer, based on their individual habits. AIswitch is designed to remove the hassle in energy switching and works for free to reduce your energy bills. I was working as frontend developer(React.JS, CSS) for the first 2 months, and then I took over the whole project to

improve/maintain the site.

December 2014 - August 2016

SENIOR LARAVEL, DJANGO DEVELOPER At Pleura Technologies Inc - Full Time

My client asked me to take over an existing codebase, do an audit of the current code and then continue in an ongoing role for optimising, upgrading, developing.

The primary skillsets was PHP, Laravel, python, Django, Postgres as well as strong understanding of APIs(SOAP, REST API, etc). There was also a need for a frontend team to help create an improved user experience across the site.

EDUCATION

2004 - 2008

Master's degree, Computer Engineering | Kyoto University